<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Something written in answer to a lying, scandalous book printed for E.B. in Pauls Church-yard, as he calls it, whose lies and slanders are denied by the children of Light, who in scorn are called Quakers, which book is proved to be a work of darkness: the author of it is said to be called Powel, who sold a copy of it for ten shillings, and now and then a flagon of beer, and would not have his name declared: so here your fruits is known of your trees, which are to be cut down and cast into the fire, and when you are there, remember you were warned. Also a declaration against the lies and slanders which are printed for G: Horton, that upon the truth they should not rest, but with the power and life of God be denyed; and who sees the end of them who makes lies their refuge, who are swept away with the beesom of destruction; which shall be witnessed with that of God in every one of your consciences: and them whom you in scorn call Quakers, from them is given forth who are in the Light that comprehends your deceits, seeth them that they are to be condemned with the Light.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1655</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 25 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A93921</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S5707</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E848_14</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99862553</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99862553</idno>
            <idno type="VID">168227</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A93921)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 168227)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 128:E848[14])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Something written in answer to a lying, scandalous book printed for E.B. in Pauls Church-yard, as he calls it, whose lies and slanders are denied by the children of Light, who in scorn are called Quakers, which book is proved to be a work of darkness: the author of it is said to be called Powel, who sold a copy of it for ten shillings, and now and then a flagon of beer, and would not have his name declared: so here your fruits is known of your trees, which are to be cut down and cast into the fire, and when you are there, remember you were warned. Also a declaration against the lies and slanders which are printed for G: Horton, that upon the truth they should not rest, but with the power and life of God be denyed; and who sees the end of them who makes lies their refuge, who are swept away with the beesom of destruction; which shall be witnessed with that of God in every one of your consciences: and them whom you in scorn call Quakers, from them is given forth who are in the Light that comprehends your deceits, seeth them that they are to be condemned with the Light.</title>
                  <author>Stodart, Amos.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1655]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: Amos Stodard [and 5 others].</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Powel's work not traced.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "July 17".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Apologetic works --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:168227:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <argument>
               <p>Something written in Anſwer to a Lying, Scandalous Book printed for <hi>E. B.</hi> in <hi>Pauls</hi> Church-yard, as he calls it, whoſe lies and ſlanders are denied by the children of Light, who in ſcorn are called Quakers, which Book is proved to be a work of darkneſs? The Author of it is ſaid to be called <hi>Powel,</hi> who ſold a Copy of it for Ten ſhillings, and now and then a flagon of Beer, and would not have his name declared: So here your fruits is known of your Trees, which are to be cut down and caſt into the fire, and when you are there, remember you were warned.</p>
               <p>Alſo a Declaration againſt the Lies and Slanders which are Printed for <hi>G: Horton,</hi> that upon the truth they ſhould not reſt, but with the power and life of God be denyed; and who ſees the end of them who makes lies their Refuge, who are ſwept away with the Beeſom of de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction; which ſhall be witneſſed with that of God in every one of your Conſciences: And them whom you in ſcorn call Quakers, from them is given forth who are in the Light that comprehends your deceits, ſeeth them that they are to be condemned with the Light.</p>
            </argument>
            <p>A Slanderous Book printed for <hi>E. B.</hi> at the Angel in <hi>Pauls</hi> Church Yard, at he calls it, but no name ſet to the Book: So to all the Children of Light, it doth appear and is ſeen to be the works of darkneſs; and he to be one of the venomous Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures that appears not in the day, who privily ſlanders in the dark: Certain men of account in the eyes of the Lord, was ſent to E. <hi>B.</hi> his ſhop, to know who was the Author of the Book, and that gave him the Copy of Lies and Slanders againſt the People called Quakers, and it was ſaid to them that he had vowed not to tell his name, and promiſed; then after another went, to <hi>E. B.</hi> his ſhop, and inquired of the Author of the Book againſt the Quakers; and after certain words it was told him, it was one <hi>Powel</hi> that had been a Prieſt, which had Ten ſhillings for his Copy, and 40, or 50. Books, and he was a poor man, and did it for money, and a flagon of
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:168227:2"/>Beer now and then. Here all may ſee which be in the Light, how he ſells his lies, and <hi>E. B.</hi> hath printed his Lies to get gain by, and ſo ſlanders the People of God: And the Title of <hi>Powels</hi> Book, he calleth it the Quakers Mountebanck, which is <hi>Powels</hi> own; or the Jeſuits turn'd Quakers. All the honeſt hearted and right minded that love and fear God, will witneſs againſt thee to be a Lyar, and that in thy conſcience ſhall witneſs againſt thee in the day of thy condemnation for thy lies, who art the wicked one that ſows the evil ſeed: And them that in ſcorn thou call'ſt Quakers, their Riſe thou knoweſt not, neither their Doctrine nor their Language; but haſt diſcovered thy ſelf and thy Ignorance, and Envy, Prophaneneſs, Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſimulation, Uncharitableneſs, evil Behavior, Geſture, Alms, and Ends for Money; as it was ſaid thou hadſt for the Copy 10. s. and here thy fooliſh wit, and folly hath manifeſted thy ſelf. None of them that fear the Lord, and loveth the truth, and are not given over to believe Lies, will not give thy paper the reading, except to ſee thy folly: And the Country men who be in the light and life of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt, may all take notice of thy ſillineſs, and in what a deluſion thou art, inſnared in ſubtilty, and led ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptive by the will of the Devil, and ſells thy lies for money; and haſt not, nor dareſt not to ſet thy name to thy lies and works of darkneſs. And a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain <hi>Powel,</hi> thou art vexing and fretting thy ſelf at the meeting of the people of God (that thou in ſcorn call Quakers) at a place which they have hired; which thou callſt Chappel or Tavern, which now is neither, but the people of God there have met and do meet, which maketh ſuch un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſavory Spirits as thine utter forth their venomn, rage and folly; for it was the Apoſtles practice, who taught in his own hired houſe two years toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Kingdom of God, who denyed the Temple and Jewiſh Synagogues, and witneſſed Chriſt Jeſus the ſecond Prieſthood, at whoſe practice the Heathen raged, as now they do, ſuch as are given over to believe lies; and <hi>Powel,</hi> thou haſt bewitcht the people with thy lies for money, like the Doctor <hi>Simon Magus:</hi> But now thy God is known, what thou ſerveſt and whom you ſerve; the Children of Light with thy lies thou canſt not deceive. In the beginning of thy Book, thou ſets ſome Scriptures for thy cloak to blinde the peoples eyes with a form of Godlineſs: But in the Life that gave forth the Scriptures, thou art judged and eke condemned who haſt got the ſheeps clothing, but inwardly art a ravening Wolf, and thy ſpeech is known, who art he that ſows the Tares, the Enemy and the ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſpirit, which the ſpirit of the Lord ever judged, and thou ſayeſt they ſhall deceive the very Elect: Proclaimed thou art here Lyar, to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to Chriſts words, who ſaith, <hi>If it were poſſible, they ſhould deceive the very Elect;</hi> and doth not ſay as thou ſaiſt, they ſhall deceive the very Elect; and here recorded thou art with the Spirit of the Lord God to be the lying ſpirit and the falſe, which the Children of Light are to beware of, and with the light condemned, for now out of thy mouth, thou falſe Prophet, comes the Blaſphemy. But many ſhall ſay, We have propheſied in thy Name, but he ſhall ſay unto you, I know you not, Depart; and many we ſee are transforming themſelves into an Angel of Light, and as the Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:168227:2"/>of Righteouſneſs, getting their form; and he that hath the form and not the power, turn away from ſuch, ſaith the Apoſtle, and with the life and power we are brought to turn away from ſuch, according to the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles Command; which makes the Heathen to rage, which hath a form of godlineſs, but not the power; and thou maiſt prevail with thy lying Spirit, with ſuch as are given over to believe lies; but the Children of Light do comprehend and ſee thee with the light, which condemns thee and thy lies: Thou talkeſt, The man is bleſt that meditates in the Law of God day and night, but thou art far from that: and then thou falleſt a railing againſt them thou calleſt Quakers and Tremblers: <hi>David</hi> was a Trembler, that delighted in the Law of God, who had Songs made of him by the ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neration of Lyars, of which thou art one in nature: And thou ſaiſt, we refuſe Dignities and Magiſtrates, and reject the word; how is lie added to lie? and deſpiſe and reject all books and learning, here is heaps of thy lies; and ſaiſt, they caſt away the Counſel of Chriſt, here is another lie; but in this thou haſt, and taken money for thy lies, <hi>Judas</hi> like; and thou art he who ſprings up in the night, whoſe works are ſeen in the night, who art tormented that the Children of light goeth from City to City, which preacheth the fear of God, the everlaſting Goſpel to men that dwell upon the earth, which diſcovers thy works of darkneſs; whoſe mouth barks out the ſwelling nonſence as thou ſpeakſt of, as beforementioned may be read, who wouldſt devour like the fox, but thou art chained; who barks in the night, yet ſtands nameleſs; thou ſaiſt they never keep time nor method. Thy method, and that which feeds all your wiſdom, is with the ſpirit of the Lord denied, who are in the conſounded language of <hi>Babel,</hi> where the Beaſt ſits; and thou and thy mother of harlots, which are both judged with the life of God, who art the man thou ſpeakeſt of full of words, which ſhall not proſper. And friend, in thy calamity remember thoſe words, and in the day of thy diſtreſs, when thou enters into that where there is no Reſt; from him who ſaith, Depart, of thy blood I am clear, upon thy own head let it be; and all thy jeers, ſcorns, and unſavory ſpeeches, to thy ſelf ſhall return home; and Dignity and Miniſtery of God is owned, as the Scripture declares, with the life that gave forth the Scriptures: and thou art he who loves the dark, whoſe light and lightneſs, thou in thy liberty haſt uttered forth, who in the doctrine of the Devil art found; and many words in that which thou calleſt the Doctrine, is not worth mentioning: And that which thou calleſt their language and diſcipline, is thy own, and ſhall ſtand for thy ſelf: And that which thou calleſt their policy, manifeſteth thy own nakedneſs and folly, and proves it, who appears in the laſt days, whoſe froath now foam out, but is afraid of the pot; but a fire is kindling, and many are ſcumming of the filth, and this meſſage ſhall ſtand, that in thy conſcience ſhall witneſs, that which governs thee is Antichriſt and ungod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; and thou that cauſt not witneſs the ſpirit of the Lord poured upon thee, as openly thou haſt declared; with it thou art recorded in the lying ſpirit thou art, whoſe madneſs appears, but with the light reproved, and thy End is ſeen: and that which thou calleſt preſumption, is thy own, and whom
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:168227:3"/>to thy ſelf ſhall return, who hath the head where is the names of Blaſphe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my; and that which thou calls the merit, is denyed by that which bridles the will, where free-grace is received; who art worſe then <hi>Balaam,</hi> who hath taken money to ſlander, and belye, and reproach the people of God; but thy filthy dreams thou ſpeakeſt of ſhall home to thy ſelf return, who art one of the unclean ſpirits which out of the bottomleſs pit comes, which hath long cauſed our Nation and Land to ſtinck with ſuch unſavory ſmells. And whereas thou ſpeakeſt of their prophaneneſs and uncleanneſs, this as is ſaid to thee before, ſhall home to thy ſelf return, who art <hi>Eſau</hi> like, as is manifeſt; and of <hi>Iſrael</hi> we are and of the houſe of God, and it we do not go about to pluck down; but thy old houſe now comes to be ſhaken which is upon the ſands, who turns the grace of God into laſciviouſneſs: and there is no Scripture ſpeaks of a Sacrament; and them that are able to try Miniſters, the Children of Light do own, and not deny them as thou ſaiſt: and here the lying ſpirit is tryed, and many other lyes thou haſt declared which be not worth mentioning, thou haſt ſuch an unſavory ſmell. And the Ordinances which God hath ſet apart is witneſſed, which the lying ſpirit doth not, who art as black as the pitch thou ſpeakeſt of ſeen with the light: And whereas thou ſaiſt, their diſſimulation, envy and uncharitable<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, ſhall ſtand for thy ſelf; for thy envy thou haſt uttered, and thy un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charitableneſs thou haſt uttered and proclaimed abroad, and thy diſſimu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation is ſeen by all the children of light; for which diſſembling thou haſt money, and of the world thou muſt have a praiſe, which lies in wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>edneſs. But now the chief Sheepherd is riſen, which keeps the Lambs from thy mouth, and the Law and Goſpel is witneſſed, and thou ſeen to be given up to believe lies, whoſe foundations muſt be razed down, which the foundation of God ſtands ſure, which all your windes, maliciouſneſs and reviles cannot ſhake; the Lord forgive thee, we revile not, but ſpeak the truth in thy conſcience, that this great ſin may not be laid to thy charge, and the Printers which publiſhed the lies; for this brings in your gains <hi>Diana</hi>-like, in publiſhing your ſorcery and lies: Fine Crafts men! but chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of light will buy none of thy ware, but ſee thy folly, and with them art judged; and thou haſt manifeſted of what Colledge thou art of, and what School thou haſt learned, and who is thy Maſter; which is denyed with the Children of Light, who witneſs Chriſt the Maſter, and learn of him: And whereas again thou ſaiſt [their Ignorance] this again is thy own, and in this thou haſt ſhewed it, and the darkneſs, as in the ſtate of the Night, Bats and Owls thou ſpeakſt of, who loves the darkneſs more then the light, whoſe evil deeds appears, and among the Prophets of the Lord God comes not, in their way, life and light, which with it art condemned; ſo the blinde leading the blinde, ſhall not both fall into the ditch: And as thou ſaiſt, their behavior, geſture, alms and ends, this ſtands for thy ſelf; thy geſture is known, thy ends is ſeen, and thy behavior recorded, unlearn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, an enemy to Iſraels Commonwealth, and the Lyon roars becauſe he wants his prey: Thou who ſpeaks of a Call; that which doth call to holi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, thou art an enemy to, who rails and lies for money, backbites for
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:168227:3"/>money, and ſlanders the Children of Light for money: So the fear of God is not before thy eyes, who maketh a ſcoff at inſpiration-teaching. Here thou haſt ſhewed thy ground; thou haſt ſhewed thy Principles, and ſhewed thy Religion; and who hath been thy School-maſter, who art unnurtered in the things of God; but from them ſeparated, who ſaith, the revilings againſt God, Chriſt and Scriptures, which are lies, and all the lies and unſavory Expreſſions which thou ſpeakeſt of, we deny, and the untruths which thou ſlandereth the people of God withal, which meet at the place called the Mouth, are condemned by the light, home to thy ſelf to return, with all thy lying ſtories: and whereas thou ſaiſt [their Geſtures] this is thy own, who art ſhameleſs and not in thy modeſty, and the yellings, whin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, when thou art in thy miſery, Remember what thou ſcoffeſt at in thy life time, and haſt made a trade in uttering Lyes and Slanders againſt the children of light for money; and whereas thou ſpeakeſt of their alms and ends, thoſe whom thou ſcornfully callſt Quakers, their ends thou ſeeſt not who thy ſelf ſeeſt not, and thou haſt ſhot with thy arrows, but haſt not hit: But the arrows of the Almighty ſhall at thee be ſhot, and in thee ſtick whoſe bow is bent: And in the pure Religion, thy diviſions thou canſt not ſow among the children of Light, neither doth thy deluſions enter, and to thy ſelf inrich thee little credit. And all the Magiſtrates which fear the living God will us own, and witneſs to be of God; we have a witneſs of God in all your conſciences: And here we have brought your works to light, and deny the works of darkneſs, and are juſtified in the fight of God and all conſciences, and are bold in the Lord to declare againſt thy lies and ſlanders; and their charity may and ſhall judge thee and all thy ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neration. Was there ſome made to go naked amongſt you, as a ſign and figure of your nakedneſs, which wanted the cloathing of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt, the Lord of Righteouſneſs, which to you and among you was a ſign and a wonder, as the ſervant of the Lord God <hi>Iſrael</hi> was: And whereas <hi>Pharaohs</hi> lean ill-favored kine, which devours the fat and the fair ones, [Religion] this needs no further interpretation, but the light which mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſteth thou and thy generation to be in the ſteps, who eats up the fat and devours them that are fed, ſeen with the light, and with it comprehended, as the Goals in <hi>England</hi> may witneſs againſt thy generation of Teachers, which ſerves not the Lord Jeſus Chriſt, but your own bellies which is your God, who glory in your ſhame, whoſe mouths muſt be ſtopped; who ſpeaks great ſwelling words, having the perſons of men in admiration becauſe of your advantage; but none you have from the children of Light, who are in the Spirit who gave forth the Scriptures. And many other lies is in the Book, as Jeſuits and Papiſts, which all are denyed with the Light, which are not worth a mentioning, but home to thy ſelf return, by them whom the world in ſcorn calls Quakers, who are in the light, life and power that doth ſhake and remove that which muſt be ſhaken, that that which cannot be ſhaken may appear and remain: So without the Government of Chriſt thou art, and all ſuch as believe thy Doctrine, which makes lies thy re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuge, which muſt be ſwept away with the Beeſom of deſtruction: So you
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:168227:4"/>Printers and Stationers, Beware leſt you be found under that Propheſie, which ſaith, <hi>Report, and we will Report;</hi> ye all with the light will be ſeen and manifeſt; which light ſhall be witneſſed with the light in your con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſciences, in the great day of the Lord. So now you have time, prize it, leaſt you ſay you had time, and it is paſt; This is the day of your viſitation: But if you ſay, our craft muſt go down, ſo ſaid <hi>Diana,</hi> when the truth was preached, which truth now throws down all deceits; and remember <hi>E. B.</hi> thou in thy life time art warned, and <hi>Powel</hi> who art with the light ſeen, and thy ſmell is ſavored, thy Language is known, and thy lie is ſeen, and thou weighed in the ballance, and thou found too light, and thy meaſure is too ſhort, and thy weights is too light, who the Serpent muſt feed, but the ſeed of God canſt not, but with it art bruiſed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>G. Horton,</hi> A Paper is printed by thee, and no other Name ſubſcribed to it, it therefore thou muſt father; all thy ſlanders in it, upon thee we lay, for it is the fruit that comes out of the old bottle, and from the envious man, which is that evil ſeed which grows upon the thorny ground, and the ſtony ground, and that which brings forth Bryars and Thorns, thy ſeed may receive, which is nigh unto curfing, and to be rejected, and the Title of thy paper thou call'ſt, The Quakers Beacon fired, and many un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>favory expreſſions in it, which be not worth mentioning, which the honeſt ſimple-hearted will not give ear to the reading of it, except to diſcover thy folly; but now it doth appear how the wicked fret themſelves and gnaw their tongues, ſuch as are wholly given up to believe lies, caſt out all their filthy ſtuff upon the Children of light, but praiſed be God it doth not touch them nor ſtain their garments, who are made white with the blood of the Lamb; for though now the Sea roars and foams, and the Lyons roars becauſe they have not their prey, yet God it is that ſtops their their mouthes, and hath ſet the bounds of the Sea that the waves they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not paſs. And thoſe which you in ſcorn calls Quakers, do witneſs, Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king and ſhaking away that which muſt be ſhaken, and winnowing of that which muſt be winnowed, according to the Scriptures, which the holy men of God did witneſs, and a Hell, and the Beeſom of deſtruction which ſweeps all that makes lies their refuge; for ſuch forgets God, and muſt be turned into Hell, and that doth wickedly: and this ſhalt thou witneſs, <hi>G. Horton:</hi> and the Miniſters of Jeſus Chriſt we own according to the Scriptures, and Revelations we own according to the Scriptures, for none knows the Son but the Father, neither knows any man the Father but the Son, and he to whom the Son reveals him: and thou that makes a ſcoff at this, makes a ſcoff at the Revelation of the Son of God, and the end of thy Religion is ſeen; and Heaven is Gods Throne, and Earth is his footſtool, and all the Laws that are good we own, which thou ſays we ſweep away; but the cuſtom of thy ſin hath taken away the ſenſe of it. And then thou ſpeakeſt much of a people called Ranters, and much thou bringeſt of their con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditions and practices againſt them, which thou in ſcorn callſt Quakers; but their condition and thy condition is denyed with the ſpirit of truth. And thou ſaiſt, they deſpiſe the Miniſters of the Word, that is another of
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:168227:4"/>thy lies, for the Miniſters of the Letter is denyed by them, which thou in ſcorn calls Quakers, which are the Miniſters of the word, who are made able Miniſters of the Spirit, but not of the Letter; and that of <hi>Jude</hi> ſhall ſtand for thy ſelf, being one that is ſeparated from the Spirit of God, and a Reprobate concerning the Faith; and Faith that works by love is owned. And the laſt Paper put forth againſt your lies, clears and ſhews the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurrection and witneſſing of it: And the Faith, the gift of God is received, which Faith works by love: And your Ordinances of men are denied, and are not to be touched nor taſted, as the Apoſtle ſaith, and the Churches of the world are denyed, and that Church which is in God is witneſſed, <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 1.1. And them that are deceived by you, are bewitched as the <hi>Gallathians</hi> was; and who are kept under thy lies, are deceived by thee as <hi>Simon Magus</hi> was; but the light of God is riſen (glory to him for ever) and thy Lies are diſcovered, and them that makes lies their refuge; and the Swine do cry, and the Dogs bark, and the Beaſts do run, which makes many people to admire and wonder, and deſpiſe at the works of the Lord, which makes many ears to tingle; but wonderers and deſpiſers periſh: and you which are quite run beſides Scripture, ſenſe and reaſonables, have ſet your ſelves as a Beacon for all to look at; a Generation of Lyars, which ſaith, the Devils Miniſters hath transformed themſelves into the Miniſters of Righteouſneſs, when the Scripture doth not ſay ſo. O Blaſphemers, for if the Devil can transform himſelf into Righteouſneſs, let all the up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right judge whether this be not quite contrary to the Scriptures; but this is like unto the reſt of the lies in thy book, which is not worth mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; but in the day of thy calamity remember, how in thy proſperity how fruitful thou was in the works of darkneſs, and ſowing thy lies; but the way of the wicked ſhall be ſtopped, which ſhall into Hell be turned, who art ſeen to be one of them to come under the Propheſie, who ſaith, Report, and we will report, whoſe Tongues are bent to tell lies, and ſlanders their Neighbors privily: Againſt whom, the Lords hand is turned, and his Bow bent, when his Arrows ſtick faſt in your ſides: Remember in the day of your ſlaughter, in your life-time you was warned, and this was love to your ſouls; and many unſavory words be in thy paper which is not worth men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioning, but home to thy ſelf ſhall return, but thy unſavory ſmell is into the Nation aſcended, which comes from the unclean Spirit, which ſuch long have cauſed the Nation to ſtinck. But the Lord is riſing by his mighty power, who will take away theſe filthy and noiſom ſmells, by and in whoſe power we are preſerved, which drives away the refuge of lies, and the Ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ars to the Lake of fire, and that in your Conſciences in the day of con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demnation and calamity ſhall witneſs us (whom you in ſcorn call Quakers; whom you in your life-time make a trade in Printing lies, ſlanders, and falſe reports againſt them) to be friends of your ſouls, and your eternal Good, and ſo the Lord forgive you that this great ſin be not laid to your charge: Every one ſhall have reward according to their works: Your re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward will be great and heavy, though now you may lead your life as him that Chriſt ſpoke of, who went into the torment and fire, who had plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:168227:5"/>in his life-time, there is an example for you; but at this you may ſnuff, as the wilde Aſs ſpoken of in <hi>Jeremy:</hi> but there is a moneth when you ſhall be taken, and then think on us: Conſider what was ſpoken in thy life-time, from them whom you in ſcorn call Quakers.</p>
            <p>And in the Scout is printed by <hi>R. Wood</hi> for <hi>G. Horton;</hi> In it is found many lies and ſlanders againſt thoſe people whom he ſcornfully calls Quakers, but all the lies and ſlanders is condemned with the Light, and the Lyars with them: <hi>G. Horton,</hi> mention the woman that is gone beyond the Sea, the Pilgrimage as thou ſaiſt; elſe for ever let thy mouth be ſtopt.</p>
            <p>Alſo more ſlanderous Speeches is uttered by thou <hi>Walker,</hi> as the Quakers black Error, which black Error is thy own, for to the truth we are con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verted from thy black Error: Therefore the venomn thou haſt uttered forth againſt the children of Light, with which Light, thou lyar and thy lies are condemned to the Lake of Fire, which burns, which cannot be quenched.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>From them whom you in ſcorn call Quakers.</hi>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Amos Stodard.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>John Bolton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Simon Dring.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Gerrard Roberts.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Robert Rich.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Robert Dring.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list> 
                  <hi>In the Name of themſelves and the reſt.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
